homebusinessmag.com 2019-04-05

# Privacy Policy | Home Business Magazine

**Effective Date: May 23, 2018**

This Privacy Policy applies to websites, apps, and other services operated by United Marketing & Research Company, Inc. (‘Home Business Media’ or ‘we’).

Safeguarding your privacy is very important to us. We are committed to protecting each User’s privacy in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We take the collection of personal information from our Users seriously. We use the term User to include any individual who accesses and uses any of our services, including (a) subscriptions to print and digital versions of Home Business Magazine (the ‘Magazine’); (b) our websites, digital applications, and online services, including HomeBusinessMag.com and HomeBusinessExpo.com (the ‘Websites’); (c) live events and conferences (if applicable); (d) our premium services if applicable (e) surveys (if applicable), and (f) surveys, contests and sweepstakes (together, the ‘Services’). Please carefully review our information collection practices and privacy protections below.

## WHO WE ARE AND HOW TO CONTACT US

Mansueto Ventures LLC owns and operates the Services. You may contact us directly if you have any questions regarding the content and material on the Website or if you have any questions about our privacy policies. Please contact us at customerservice(at)homebusinessmag-dot-com or Privacy Officer, United Marketing & Research Co., Inc., 20664 Jutland Place, Lakeville, MN 55044.

## DATA CONTROLLER

The data controller for the information you provide or that is collected pursuant to this Privacy Policy is: United Marketing & Research Co., Inc., 20664 Jutland Place, Lakeville, MN 55044.

## INFORMATION COLLECTED

We provide various informative, educational, and entertaining features as part of the Services. To operate these features, we collect certain non-personal and personal information from our Users for specific purposes. For Website-related activities that request personal information, you agree to provide accurate and current information about yourself. We may retain personal information for an indefinite amount of time to preserve our database and to comply with various federal and state laws. We may conduct contests, sweepstakes and/or special events through the Websites. To participate in these events, you must meet the designated criteria for participation, and minimum age requirements (example, twenty-one (21) years of age or older) for the specific event.

## HOW INFORMATION IS USED

To gauge the effectiveness of the Websites, we may collect non-personal information about our Users, such as Internet server and browser identification, the Internet service provider, clickstream information, web pages visited, the web page from which a person enters our site, duration of visit and domain type. We may produce certain contests, sweepstakes and special events with the support of promotional partners and/or affiliated or non-affiliated sponsors. The information collected through the Websites in conjunction with such events may also be used for the marketing of additional services and events by us and/or our promotional partners and sponsors beyond the contest, sweepstakes and/or special event. Depending on the event, Users either grant their approval on how their information is used before it is collected (‘opt-in’), or choose to deny use of their information for additional purposes (‘opt-out’).

To participate in certain activities on the Websites or in online activities, special events, contests, sweepstakes or other Services, you may be required to provide your name, street and e-mail addresses, telephone number, birth date and gender. We also may survey Users about various topics, including how we can improve our Websites and Services. Response to our surveys is entirely voluntary. We collect information for several important purposes, including to protect the security of our Users and the Services, operate our Services, improve our Services, distribute our newsletters, notify the winners of our contests and sweepstakes, allow participation in specified activities and for future marketing and/or promotional use in connection with the Services; and other products and services provided by us.

For each contest, sweepstakes or event, we will provide notice of the applicable rules or terms for the event, and if necessary, post any supplemental terms and conditions or privacy provisions. To the extent there is a conflict between those privacy provisions and this Privacy Policy, the privacy provisions for the specific event will govern (but solely to extent of the conflict).

## POLICY ON DISCLOSING YOUR INFORMATION TO PARTIES OTHER THAN HOME BUSINESS MEDIA

We only share or disclose your personal information with companies other than Home Business Media when it is required by law, disclosure is necessary to operate the Services, to protect the safety of our Users, employees or property and/or when disclosure is consistent with Home Business Media’ practices for its Services. We may in the future share personal information with our parents, partners, affiliates or other entities for other purposes. If we decide to enter into such sharing arrangements, we will disclose to our Users and in this Privacy Policy the name of each entity with which we will share information, how the information will be used, what type of information will be shared, and how to contact us if you do not want us to share your personal information.

We may collect and provide aggregate information about our Users to our advertisers, sponsors, promotional partners, and affiliates, such as activity or the likes and dislikes of our Users, or how many persons visited a particular page, but this information generally does not include personal information about any individual User. We may obtain geographic information such as zip code clustering from other sources, but this aggregate information will not reveal any personal information about specific Users.

## USE AND COLLECTION OF INFORMATION BY OPERATIONAL PROVIDERS

For the convenience of our Users, we may provide the opportunity to purchase certain goods, merchandise and services through the Services. Companies other than Home Business Media may handle some of these transactions. We call the companies that conduct our e-commerce operations, order fulfillment and/or contract services ‘operational providers.’ If you choose to use these Services, our operational providers will request information to fulfill your order or request. The voluntary submission of your personal information to these operational providers, including your order or request, is governed by the specific operational provider privacy and other terms. To facilitate an order or request, we may share information with the operational provider. The operational provider may also share your information with us. We will store this information in our User database. In most instances, we request that our operational providers adhere to the provisions in this Privacy Policy and only share Users’ personal information with us, unless necessary to complete a User’s request or order. We also request that these providers only use the personal information for the purpose of conducting the sale or fulfilling the requested service or order. However, you must read an operational provider’s privacy policy to determine the extent of use and disclosure of your personal information collected by them. Home Business Media, its parents, affiliates and subsidiaries are not responsible for the collection, use and disclosure practices of operational providers, nor is Home Business Media responsible or liable for the products or services provided by operational providers.

## USE OF TRACKING DEVICES AND COOKIES

A cookie is a small data file that contains a unique identification number that a website places on your hard drive when you visit a site. Our Websites use cookies or other tracking devices. The ‘cookie’ is able to store information such as the type of browser you use, data about your computer, and how many times your computer visits a certain site. Cookies enable us to track how often Users are visiting our Websites and specific pages, the estimated audience size for sponsors and advertisers, the number of entries in specific events, and user preferences. You can refuse to use cookies by turning them off in your browser. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use most of the Websites. However, you may find that some areas on the Websites will be slower, or may not function at all, and you may not be able to participate in certain activities such as contests or sweepstakes if the cookies are disabled. The Websites may use clear GIFs [Graphics Interchange Formats] (also known as web beacons, pixel tags, or web bugs). A clear GIF is a line of code programmed to collect certain information about a visit to a particular website. We may use GIFs to gather aggregate information on visits to our Websites, assist with registration and other features, and track usage of Website links. Other websites that you may link to through the Websites also may use clear GIFs. Home Business Media, its parents and subsidiaries are not responsible for the use of clear GIFs by other website operators. Users must review other website operators’ privacy policies to determine the type and extent of tracking devices used.

## USE AND COLLECTION OF INFORMATION BY THIRD PARTY COOKIES AND TRACKING DEVICES; ADVERTISERS AND SPONSORS

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on the Websites. These advertising companies may collect and use information (not including your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number) about your visits to our site and other websites not owned and operated by us, and may also combine this information with other data about your purchases and interests from other online and offline sources, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. In addition, we may share usage information about Users of the Websites with these companies for the purpose of managing and targeting advertisements and for market research analysis on the Websites and other websites. For these purposes, we and our third party advertising companies may note some of the pages you visit on the Websites through the use of GIFs. In the course of serving advertisements to the Websites, our third party advertisers may place or recognize a unique ‘cookie’ on your computer. The Websites may post banner ads and other forms of advertisements, and/or links to the websites of affiliate entities or of advertisers or sponsors who are companies that are not owned or operated by us, or our affiliates or subsidiaries. These entities may independently solicit and collect personal information, or send their own cookies and/or clear GIFs to our Users. The data collected is used in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to Users of the Websites and other interactive media and may be used to keep track of user response to each advertisement. We also work with online targeting companies and third-party data analytics. Some of these companies may use non-personal information (not including your name, address, telephone number or email address) about your visits to the Websites and other websites in order to provide targeting recommendations and data based on which we may provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

Many third-party companies we may work with are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), a cooperative on analytics companies and online marketing committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices. The NAI has developed a tool that allows consumers to opt out of targeted advertising delivered by NAI members’ ad networks. To learn more about how to use the tool or opting out of targeted advertising, go to  **<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/>**.

Following are the names and websites of some of the other companies who may set cookies on our sites to serve or present the ads that appear on our sites and to conduct research about the advertisements. You may learn about opt outing of their targeted advertising programs by going to their respective websites.

Collective Media – www.collective-media.com/privacy

Context Web – www.contextweb.com/ppolicy.html

Dynamic Logic – www.dynamiclogic.com/na/company/privacypolicy

Eyeblaster – www.eyeblaster.com/privacy.asp

Google Analytics – www.google.com/intl/en_ALL/privacy.html

Hitwise – www.hitwise.com/other/privacy-policy.php

InsightExpress – www.insightexpress.com/main.asp?pageID=143

Interpolls – www.interpolls.com/privacy.html

Jupiter Media Metrix – www.internet.com/corporate/privacy/privacypolicy.html

Mediaplex – www.mediaplex.com/mojo_privacy_statement.shtml

Omniture – www.omniture.com/en/privacy/policy#optout

Pointroll – www.pointroll.com/privacy-policy.aspx

Quantcast – www.quantcast.com/docs/privacy

Quigo – www.quigo.com/privacy.htm

Unicast – www.unicast.com/privacy-policy.aspx

Please be advised that when you link to or visit an advertiser’s or sponsor’s website, we may frame the site with our website logo; however, you will be subject to the privacy policy and terms of usage agreement of that website operator. Home Business Media, its parents, affiliates or subsidiaries will not be responsible for advertiser or sponsor ads and/or links or the content, information collection, activities, use and disclosure practices of the websites of advertisers and sponsors. We may also provide co-branded promotions or services with certain sponsors or other entities. As a part of these services or promotions, we may request the submission of your personal information through the Websites for participation and/or registration. We may also share your information with the sponsor or entity participating in the service or promotion to fulfill your request. If the co-sponsor or other entity collects your personal information, they may also share your information with us.

## SECURITY PROCEDURES

We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

The criteria used to determine our retention periods include:

  * Whether there is a legal obligation to which we are subject (for example, certain laws require us to keep records of your transactions for a certain period of time before we can delete them)
  * The length of time we have an ongoing relationship with you and provide services to you (for example, for as long as you have an account with us or keep using the Websites);
  * Whether retention is advisable; and considering our legal position (such as, for statutes of limitations, litigation or regulatory investigations).

Only supervisors and employees with specific authorization have access to databases containing Users’ personal information. Credit card information is transmitted via encrypted technology. If we decide to share User information with other members of the Home Business Media ventures, the receiving entity will also maintain the integrity and security of that User information. That said, it is not possible to guarantee the security or integrity of information you disclose online since a sufficiently powerful attack from an unauthorized third party, despite being highly unlikely, could compromise your information.

## WEBSITE LISTS

For the convenience of our Users, we may offer a list of helpful website links provided by other entities and/or persons. We do not endorse or recommend, nor are we liable for, the products or services of any websites not owned or operated by us. When you visit other websites you will also be subject to the privacy policies and terms of usage agreements, if any, of that website operator.

## CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

Home Business Media respects the privacy of your child and we want to share with you our policies regarding children under the age of thirteen (13). Although Users of all ages may navigate through the Services, we do not knowingly collect personal information from persons under the age of thirteen (13). If upon notification by a parent or guardian, or discovery by other means, that a child under thirteen (13) has improperly registered by using false information, we will immediately cancel the child’s membership and/or participation and delete the child’s personal information from our records.

## YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR INFORMATION

If you would like to review, update, correct, restrict, suppress, or delete personal information that you have previously provided to us, or if you would like to receive an electronic copy of your personal information for purposes of transmitting it to another company (if this right to data portability is provided to you by law), you can contact us at customerservice(at)homebusinessmag-dot-com or by mail to United Marketing & Research Co., Inc., 20664 Jutland Place, Lakeville, MN 55055

In your request, please make clear what personal information you would like to have changed, whether you would like to have your personal information suppressed from our database, or other limitations you would like to put on our use of your personal information. For your protection, we only fulfill requests for the personal information associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before fulfilling your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

Please note that we often need to retain certain data for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transaction that you began prior to requesting a change or deletion (e.g., when you make a purchase or enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the personal information provided until after the completion of such purchase or promotion). We also may not allow you to review certain data for legal, security or other reasons. In addition, our databases and other records may have residual data which will not be removed.

If at any time you believe that the Services have not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please let us know. We will use good faith efforts to determine and correct the problem.

If you are an EEA resident, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a [data protection authority](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080) about how we process your personal information.

## CHANGES IN THE PRIVACY POLICY

The effective date at the top of this page indicates when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Any change is effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy. We will notify you before any material change takes effect so that you have time to review the changes. Your use of the Services following these changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy.
